Guide to the Asian CineVision Records TAM.416
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III: Video Recordings, 545120
  - Video 238: CCTV, April 27, 1980; Cuid9284 (Box 92, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9284)
    This episode includes four sections: street interviews, excerpts of a cultural performance, a travel program, and interviews with martial art performers. The first part includes street interviews with Chinatown residents. Interviewees express views on the changes of Chinatown, such as the expansion of the Chinese population, and the increasing number of stores and garment manufacture factories. The second part shows excerpts of Chinese Cultural Center's performance at Murry Bergtraum High School. The third part is a program called Travelogue (). In this episode, Sheepshead Bay in New York City, New York state is introduced. The fourth section introduces a martial art school in Chinatown. The host interviews the school master and Chinese traditional dancing lion performers.
  - Video 239: CCTV, May 4, 1980; Cuid9285 (Box 92, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9285)
    This episode features videos created by participants of CCTV's Production and Performance Workshop held in 1979, the fourth of such sessions. Videos include an advertisement for ballpoint pens, street interviews, a cooking lesson, and a short drama. Interviews with the workshop trainees are also included in this episode.
  - Video 240: CCTV, May 11, 1980; Cuid9286 (Box 93, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9286)
    This episode has three parts: a travel program, a social service program, and a feature report on a Chinese singer. The first part is a program called Travelogue (). This episode features the Brooklyn Botanical Garden. The second part is Hello Mother (), in which the hosts interview Ms. Kwan about cosmetic and makeup skills. After the interview, Ms. Kwan has a makeup demonstration. The third part of the video features singing performances by Chinese singer Zi Wei ().
  - Video 241: CCTV, May 18, 1980; Cuid9287 (Box 93, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9287)
    This episode includes five sections: a feature report on a labor strike, street interviews, a cultural program, an interview with Chinese playwright Cao Yu (), and a 13-minute Hong Kong documentary. The first part features a labor strike outside Silver Palace Restaurant in Chinatown. An unequal allocation of tips is the main issue. In the second part, hosts interview Chinatown residents about their views on the Silver Palace Restaurant labor strike. The third part features a special program called Asian American Experience, in which Asian-American young people are preparing for the American Heritage Week exhibition. The fourth section covers interviews with Chinese playwright Cao Yu. The fifth section of the episode shows documentary Old Man and His Painting () (1977), in which Chinese painter Ting Yin Yung ()'s life in Hong Kong is documented.
  - Video 242: CCTV, May 24, 1980; Cuid9288 (Box 93, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9288)
    This episode includes three parts: a coverage of a cultural activity, a social service program, and a feature report of a martial arts contest. The first part covers the second Annual Asian-Pacific American Heritage Festival held at Lincoln Center. The second part is a program called At Your Service (), in which the Chinatown Daycare Center is featured. The third part features a martial arts contest.
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 60 minutes
  - Video 243: CCTV, June 1, 1980; Cuid9289 (Box 93, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9289)
    This episode includes two parts: a feature report on a film festival and coverage of a martial arts contest. The first part features the third annual Asian American International Film Festival which is co-sponsored by New York University film school and Asian CineVision. Also included in this episode are excerpts from films of the film festival: Prince Nezha's Triumph Against Dragon King () (1979), Chinese American Second Century, The New Wife, and China: The Land of My Father. The second part of the episode reports a martial arts contest.
  - Video 244: CCTV, June 8, 1980; Cuid9290 (Box 93, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9290)
    This episode includes four parts: a feature report on a film festival, coverage of a cultural activity in New Jersey, a dance performance, and interviews with CCTV workshop participants. The first section features the opening ceremony of the third annual Asian American International Film Festival which is held at the Tishman Auditorium at New York University. Excerpts of selected film festival films are also included in the episode. The second part is a report on an Asian cultural activity held in New Jersey. The third part covers Chinese classical dance performances at Murry Bergtraum High School. The fourth section includes interviews with participants at CCTV's fifth Production and Performance Workshop.
  - Video 245: CCTV, June 29, 1980; Cuid9291 (Box 93, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9291)
    This episode includes four parts: a feature on a theatrical production, a social service program, a travel program, and street interviews. The first part features the Four Seas Players at Pace University in an adaptation of the 18th century drama work Beggar's Opera. The second part is a feature program called At Your Service (). In this section, a hotel management vocational training school is introduced. The school is operated by Jack Han. The third part is a program called Travelogue (), and features the Bronx Zoo. In the fourth section, Chinatown residents are interviewed about their views on roller skating.
  - Video 246: CCTV, July 6, 1980; Cuid9292 (Box 93, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9292)
    This episode includes three parts: coverage of a cultural activity, a social service program, and street interviews. The first part features cultural performances at Pace University organized by a Hong Kong students association. The second part is a special program called At Your Service () which introduces culinary and English lessons offered by China Institute. Interviews with the institute's organizer and lesson participants are included. In the third segment, two hosts interview people about their views on current television programs and their demands for Chinese television programs.
  - Video 247: CCTV, July 13, 1980; Cuid9293 (Box 93, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9293)
    This episode includes three parts: a special program on a culture activity, a feature on a Hong Kong performance troupe's visit to New York, and coverage of a Chinatown cultural festival. The first part is a special program called Asian American Experience featuring a New York Shakespeare Festival Workshop theatrical production of FOB. The play is written by David Henry Hwang and stars Calvin Jung, John Lone, and Ginny Yang. The second part of the episode is a program called Hello Mother (). Included in this program are excerpts of Cantonese opera performed at the Sun Sing Theater by Hong Kong's Kam Lai Wah opera troupe (). Interviews with leading performers Lam Kam Tong () and Ng Kwun-Lai () are also included. The third part covers the 10th Chinatown Summer Cultural Festival.
  - Video 248: CCTV, July 20, 1980; Cuid9294 (Box 93, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9294)
    This episode includes three parts: a report of an exhibition, street interviews, and a feature on the visit of a Hong Kong performance troupe. The first part covers the 1980 China Decorative Arts Exhibition, held at the United Nations Headquarters in New York City. The second part includes street interviews with people about their views on the increasing cost of living in New York City. The third part features Hong Kong Chor Fung Ming Cantonese Opera troupe ( ) and their performances in the United States. Also included in this part are interviews with leading performers: Siu Chung-kwan (), Lung Kim Sang (), Mui Suet Sze (), Chu Kim Tang () and Yin Suet Fun (), and with the troupe's managers, So Siu-Tong () and Wong Har-wai ().
  - Video 249: CCTV, July 27, 1980; Cuid9295 (Box 94, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9295)
    This episode includes three parts: a segment on social services in Chinatown, a report on a cultural festival, and a feature about a performance troupe. The first part is a program called At Your Service () in which the Chinatown Daycare Center is featured. The second part is called Asian American Experience and covers the 1980 New York Obon Festival, a cultural event that celebrates Japanese traditional culture. The third part features the Hai Jia performance troupe (), originally from the Republic of China. Also included in the episode are the troupe's performing shows during their U.S. tour and interviews with the troupe members.
  - Video 250: CCTV, August 3, 1980; Cuid9296 (Box 94, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9296)
    This episode includes three parts: a feature on a singing contest, street interviews, and a travel program. The first section is a feature report on a CCTV-sponsored singing competition held at Murry Bergtraum High School. Candidates sing songs in Mandarin and Cantonese. The second part consists of street interviews with people about their views on sanitation issues in Chinatown. The third part is a program called Travelogue (), in which Sheepshead Bay, a neighborhood in New York City, is featured.
  - Video 251: CCTV, August 10, 1980; Cuid9297 (Box 94, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9297)
    This episode includes two parts: a feature on a public broadcasting conference, and a 26-minute Hong Kong film. The first part features the first National Conference of Asian Pacific Producers in Public Broadcasting. Excerpts of meetings and discussion sessions are included. The second part is an Allen Fong () film The Wild Child () (1977). The film depicts the life of a young boy living with his grandmother in a rural village.
  - Video 252: CCTV, August 17, 1980; Cuid9298 (Box 94, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9298)
    This episode includes four parts: a feature on a Peking opera troupe, a feature on culinary shows, a report on a martial arts performance, and a short documentary. The first part features the U.S. tour of a Peking opera troupe. Excerpts of the troupe's rehearsal are included. In the second part, culinary shows are introduced. The shows take place in Silver Palace Restaurant in Chinatown, by a number of chefs originated from Pan Xi Restaurant (), Guangzhou, People's Republic of China. The third part of the episode covers a martial arts show. The fourth section is a documentary that includes works by Chinese painter Huang Binhong ().
  - Video 253: CCTV, August 24, 1980; Cuid9299 (Box 94, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9299)
    This episode includes two parts: a feature on culinary shows, and a 26-minute Hong Kong film. In the first part, culinary shows are introduced. The shows take place in Silver Palace Restaurant in Chinatown, performed by a number of chefs originated from Pan Xi Restaurant, Guangzhou, People's Republic of China. The second part is an Allen Fong () film Song of Yuen Chau Chai () (1977), which depicts the lives of fishermen in Hong Kong.
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 50 minutes
  - Video 254: CCTV, September 14, 1980; Cuid9300 (Box 94, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9300)
    This episode features a martial art performance show at The Yung Wing Public School in Chinatown. The performance is led by Hong Kong martial art master Shih Kien ().
  - Video 255: CCTV, September 21, 1980; Cuid9301 (Box 94, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9301)
    This episode includes two parts: a feature on Chinese puppet show, and a 35-minute film. The first part features Chinese traditional puppet shows performed by the Quanzhou puppet troupe from Fujian Province, People's Republic of China. The troupe is doing a U.S. tour and had four shows at the American Museum of Natural History in New York City. The second part of the episode is a Curtis Choy film Dupont Guy: The Schiz of Grant Avenue (1976). The film narrates the struggles and experiences of being Chinese American.
  - Video 256: CCTV, October 5, 1980; Cuid9302 (Box 94, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9302)
    This episode features a 1979 martial arts competition sponsored by CCTV. The participants are of different ethnicities and are practitioners and students from different martial art schools.
  - Video 257: CCTV, October 19, 1980; Cuid9303 (Box 94, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9303)
    This episode includes four sections: a brief report on a commerce forum, a feature on the visit of a Hong Kong performance troupe, a travel program, and a 13-minute Hong Kong documentary. The first section is a brief report on the U.S. Secretary of Commerce Philip Klutznick as he attends a forum organized by Chinese American commerce organization to discuss Sino-US trade relations. The second part features Hong Kong Chor Fung Ming Cantonese Opera troupe ()'s operatic performing shows in the United States. Also included in this part are interviews with leading performers: Siu Chung-kwan (), Lung Kim Sang (), Mui Suet Sze (), Chu Kim Tang () and Yin Suet Fun (), and with troupe manager: So Siu-Tong (),Wong Har-wai (). The third part is program called Travelogue () in which the host introduces a skate rink in Brooklyn, New York, presumably the Abe Stark Rink of Coney Island. The fourth part shows documentary Old Man and His Painting () (1977), in which Chinese painter Ting Yin Yung ()'s life in Hong Kong is documented.
  - Video 258: CCTV, October 26, 1980; Cuid9304 (Box 95, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9304)
    This episode includes two parts: a report on President Jimmy Carter's Chinatown visit and a 26-minute Hong Kong film. In the first part, Jimmy Carter attends a fundraising banquet held in Silver Palace Restaurant and gives a speech. Interviews with Chinatown residents and banquet participants are also included. The second part is an Allen Fong () film Song of Yuen Chau Chai () (1977), which depicts the lives of fishermen in Hong Kong.
  - Video 259: CCTV, November 2, 1980; Cuid9305 (Box 95, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9305)
    This episode includes two parts: a feature on the 1980 presidential election and a report on the New York City marathon. In the first part, various Chinatown activities that support different candidates are featured, including a public assembly to support Reagan for president, President Jimmy Carter's visit to Chinatown, and interviews with Chinese American representatives who actively participate in campaigning. The host also interviews Virginia M. Kee () who is running for Democratic representative in New York State. Instructions on how to cast a vote are also given.The end of this program includes a coverage of the 1980 New York City marathon on October 26, with the starting point in Staten Island.
  - Video 260: CCTV, November 9, 1980; Cuid9306 (Box 95, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9306)
    This episode contains two parts: a report on a Chinese acrobatic group's performance, and a 26-minute Hong Kong film. The first part covers a Guangdong acrobatic troupe's US tour. An interview with the troupe leader and highlights of the troupe's acrobatic performance are included. The second part is an Allen Fong () film The Wild Child () (1977). The film depicts the life of a young boy who lives with his grandmother in a rural village.
  - Video 261: CCTV, November 16, 1980; Cuid9307 (Box 95, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9307)
    This episode contains three parts: a report on a Chinatown community gathering, interviews with Hong Kong celebrities, and a feature on a Hong Kong performance troupe. The first part is a community gathering at the Chinese Consolidated Benevolent Association. The purpose of the gathering is to collect opinions from Chinatown residents on the newly elected President Ronald Reagan. The second part of the episode includes interviews with two Hong Kong celebrities - singer Chelsia Chan Chau Ha () and Cantonese opera performer Chan Leung Chung (). The third part features Hong Kong Chor Fung Ming Cantonese Opera troupe ()'s operatic performances in the United States. Also included in this part are interviews with leading performers: Siu Chung-kwan (), Lung Kim Sang (), Mui Suet Sze (), Chu Kim Tang () and Yin Suet Fun (), and with troupe manager: So Siu-Tong (),Wong Har-wai ().
  - Video 262: CCTV, November 30, 1980; Cuid9308 (Box 95, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9308)
    This episode includes two parts: a report on a martial arts contest, and a 35-minute film. The first part covers a 1980 martial arts competition held at The Yung Wing Public School in Chinatown. Interviews with the first-place winner and the competition's organizer are included. The second part features a Curtis Choy film Dupont Guy: The Schiz of Grant Avenue (1976). The film narrates the struggles and experiences of being Chinese American.
  - Video 263: CCTV, December 14, 1980; Cuid9309 (Box 95, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9309)
    This episode includes three parts: a report on a Chinese exhibition, a report on the death of John Lennon, and a theatrical production. The first section covers The 1980 Exhibition of People' Republic of China held at the New York Coliseum in New York City. Participants include Ed Koch, Mayor of New York City, Chai Zemin (), Chinese Ambassador to the United States of America Ambassador, and Lai Yali (), Deputy Permanent Representative of China to the United Nations. Over a thousand people attend. On display are Chinese electronic products and cultural artifacts. The second part covers the death of John Lennon in New York City, a member of the British rock band The Beatles. The third section features a Chinese theatrical production, Old Soldier (), a co-produced by CCTV and the New York Drama Society.
  - Video 264: CCTV, December 21, 1980; Cuid9310 (Box 95, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9310)
    This episode includes two parts: a cultural program about Christmas and a television drama produced by CCTV. The first part covers Christmas activities in New York City and includes street interviews with people on their Christmas plans. The second part is a special program called "Asian American Experience" featuring a New York Shakespeare Festival Workshop of FOB. The play is written by David Henry Hwang, starring Calvin Jung, John Lone, and Ginny Yang. The third section is a single-episode television romance drama Autumn Dream () produced by CCTV Production and Performance workshop students.
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 48 minutes
  - Video 265: CCTV, December 28, 1980; Cuid9311 (Box 95, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9311)
    This episode includes two parts: a special program on John Lennon, and a 26-minute Hong Kong film. The first part pays tribute to John Lennon, a member of British rock band The Beatles who had recently been murdered in front of his apartment building in Manhattan, New York City. The second part is an Allen Fong () film Song of Yuen Chau Chai () (1977), which depicts the lives of fishermen in Hong Kong.
  - Video 266: CCTV, January 4, 1981; Cuid9312 (Box 95, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9312)
    This episode shows the 1980 martial arts competition held at The Yung Wing Public School in Chinatown. Interviews with the first-place winner and the competition's organizer are included.
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 56 minutes
  - Video 267: CCTV, January 25, 1981; Cuid9313 (Box 96, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9313)
    This episode contains three parts: a documentary, a feature on a martial arts performance, and street interviews. The first part is a special program called Asian American Experience in which a documentary about the historical exclusion and mistreatment of Asian Americans in the United States is shown. The second part features a martial arts performance held at the Murry Bergtraum High School. The third part includes street interviews with people about their views on roller skating.
  - Video 268: CCTV, February 1, 1981; Cuid 9314 (Box 96, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid 9314)
    This episode contains two parts: news coverage, and a social service program. The first part is a program called Times Magazine, which covers international, national, local and Chinatown news.The local news includes the robbery of a Chinatown jewel store, the progress of labor-employer negotiation in Chinatown's Silver Palace Restaurant, and information about a free physical examination program available to Chinatown residents. The second is called At Your Service (), which introduces culinary and English lessons offered by China Institute. Interviews with the institute's organizer and lesson participants are included.
  - Video 269: CCTV, 1981-02-15; cuid9315
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 60 min., Preservation Note: The tape could not be digitized due to advanced degradation.
  - Video 270: CCTV, March 1, 1981; Cuid2604 (Box 96, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid2604)
    This episode includes two parts: news coverage and a social service program. The first part is a news program called Times Magazine which covers international, national, local and Chinatown news. Local news cover an anniversary performance by Chinatown's Four Sea Players is held at Pace University. The second part is Hello Mother (), in which the hosts interview Ms. Kwan about cosmetic and make-up skills. After the interview, Ms. Kwan gives a makeup demonstration.
    Original Format: 3/4" Umatic Video, Duration: 60 minutes
  - Video 271: CCTV, March 8, 1981; Cuid2605 (Box 96, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid2605)
    This episode includes two parts: a feature report on a Chinese American politician and a theatrical production. The first part is a feature report on Anna Chan Chennault (), spouse of American military aviator major general Claire Lee Chennault. She attends a Chinese American event and talks about her recent visits to Beijing, People's Republic of China, and Taipei, Republic of China (Taiwan). Her visits to Asia is on behalf of the Ronald Reagan administration. The second section features Chinese drama play Old Soldier (), a co-production by CCTV and the New York Drama Society.
    Original Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 55 minutes
  - Video 272: CCTV, March 15, 1981; Cuid2606 (Box 96, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid2606)
    This episode contains three parts: news coverage, a report on a Chinatown tenant-landlord dispute, and a feature report on ethnic discrimination in the United States. The first part is a CCTV news report which covers international, national, and local news. The second part is a report about a dispute between Chinatown tenants and the landlord called Thomas Sung (). The third part features the history and current status of Chinese Americans and Asian Americans being discriminated against and stereotyped. The feature starts from the launch of a Yves Saint Laurent produced perfume called Opium. Interviews with experts and clips from the documentary The Fist of Righteous Harmony are also included. The host criticizes discrimination and stereotypes.
    Original Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 31 minutes
  - Video 273: CCTV, March 22, 1981; Cuid6207 (Box 96, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid6207)